JENNIFER ANDERSON

jennifer@memorabilist.com

118 Union St. 5A Brooklyn 11231

www.memorabilist.com

I am a senior-level UX designer and information architect with nearly 20 years of digital design experience. My specialties include user research and discovery, working with high-level stakeholders, wireframing, and rapid prototyping. My tools include Sketch, InVision, UXPin, OmniGraffle, XMind, the Adobe Creative suite, and hand-coding in HTML and CSS/Sass.

EXPERIENCE

HOOK & LOOP

Senior Information Architect

June 2015 – present

- Design and execute detailed wireframes and prototypes that illustrate layout, interactivity, and visual treatment
- Conduct user research such as interviews, surveys, and interface efficacy testing
- Guide content owners to create effective experiences
- · Work with graphic design and coding teams to iterate final UI

Current projects:

- New design direction for Infor.com (parent company website)
- Integrated use case and design documentation
- User journey mapping of high-traffic site areas
- Introduction of collaborative testing practices into current team workflow

THE NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY

Senior User Experience Designer

- into mobile-ready web interfaces
- Wireframed projects
- Translated NYPL brand to digital contexts
- Built NYPL's first rapid prototyping system

August 2007 – March 2015

- Built HTML/CSS/jQuery prototypes for development Led introduction of wireframing into standard web design process
 - Created first NYPL.org visual design patterns
 - · Co-founded content strategy working group
 - Led and executed redesign of the Digital Gallery

THE NEW YORK PUBLIC LIBRARY

Specialist, Digital Library Department

- Researched and prepared art and art books for digitization
- · Compiled and added item- and collection-lev architectural metadata to the system database

May 2006 - August 2007

THE METROPOLITAN MUSEUM OF ART

January 2006 – May 2006

Web Designer, The Thomas J. Watson Library

- Designed and planned code structure for library portal project
- Supervised meetings of library portal project committee

PRATT INSTITUTE 2003 – 2007

Web Assistant, History of Art and Design Department

- Assisted the History of Art and Design department office, including the Chair, with web and internet issues
- Built several class websites, including History of Art and Design department site
- Maintained department computers and software

FREELANCE WEB DESIGNER

2001 - 2005

Clients included Jonathan Green, international journalist; FoodHealer, food/nutrition blog; GoalQuest, internet education company; Bedford St. Martin's, publisher.

COOLFIRE.INTERACTIVE 1999 – 2001

Digital Designer

- Designed and built websites and e-card systems for clients
- Supervised art department "Design Council," including design critiques and resource library
- · Designed and programmed agency intranet

EDUCATION

PRATT INSTITUTE 2003 – 2007

MLS and MS, Library and Information Science, History of Art and Design

Thesis (History of Art and Design): "Strange Places: Illustrating the Otherworldly in Mike Mignola's Hellboy"

SMITH COLLEGE 1991 — 1995

Bachelor of Arts, Comparative Literature, Art History